<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>

<text>Dangling, upside-down rune etched in one's mind. Symbol of a hunter. By focusing one's thoughts on this rune, a hunter loses all Blood Echoes, but awakens afresh, as if it were all just a bad dream.</text>
<text>Hunters are linked by the resonance of bells with special encoded timbres. This inaudible burst disrupts such resonance. Fire to end cooperation, and prevent further cooperation. Firing this does not disrupt the resonance of a Sinister Bell.</text>
<text>Messengers are inhabitants of the dream who revere the brave hunters. Use them to send messages to other worlds. Leave notes with messengers, read the notes left to messengers in other worlds, and rate notes to reach out to hunters across planes of existence. Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.</text>
<text>Red-leather record of the Vilebloods loyal to the covenant of Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods, at Cainhurst Castle. A record of the Vilebloods, blood-lusting hunters who seek blood dregs of their prey, kept throughout the ages. Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.</text>
<text>The League staff is the sign of a confederate. A directory within the hilt lists the names of fellow confederates. Members of the League brandish this staff to indicate themselves to fellow members of the League. There shall be no sympathy for those engaged in the bloody mission of the League. No matter that an oath must be taken to uphold the illusion.</text>
<text>Great old bell discovered in the underground labyrinth. Its ring resonates across worlds, and the first hunter used it as a special signal to call hunters from other worlds to cross the gap and cooperate. A human must use Insight to ring this uncanny bell, but the benefits of cross-world cooperation are many.</text>
<text>Small bell discovered in the old underground labyrinth. Its ring resonates across worlds, and the first hunter used it as a special signal to call hunters from other worlds to cross the gap and cooperate. This bell resonates with its counterpart, the Beckoning Bell. Ring to help hunters in other worlds. Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.</text>
<text>A blood-stained bell discovered in the old underground labyrinth. One of the resonating bells that cross the gaps of worlds, but this one knells for misfortune and malice. The Sinister Bell is an object of dark thoughts. Ring it to become the enemy of a hunter in another world. Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.</text>
<text>A small music box received from a young Yharnam girl. Plays a song shared by her mother and father. Inside the lid is a small scrap of paper, perhaps an old message. Two names can be made out, however faintly. Viola and Gascoigne.</text>
<text>Blood taken from Arianna, Cathedral Ward woman of pleasure. The sweet blood of Arianna restores HP, and temporarily speeds stamina recovery. A member of the old Healing Church would know that her blood is similar indeed, to precisely what was once forbidden.</text>
<text>Blood taken from Adella, nun of the Healing Church. Restores an amount of HP, then continues to gradually restore HP for a short time. The Healing Church nuns are chosen for their merit as vessels for blood, and groomed as Blood Saints. The mere chance of being treated with their blood lends legitimacy to the Healing Church and communion.</text>
<text>Blood vial acquired from Iosefka's clinic. This refined blood, highly invigorating, restores a larger amount of HP. The product of a slow and careful refinement process, this rare blood vial appears to be a clinic original.</text>
<text>The Vilebloods of Cainhurst, blood-lusting hunters, see these frightful things in coldblood. They often appear in the blood of echo fiends, that is to say, the blood of hunters. Queen Annalise partakes in these blood dregs offerings, so that she may one day bear the Child of Blood, the next Vileblood heir.</text>
<text>Blood received from Annalise, Vileblood Queen of Cainhurst. Vileblood hunters who offer sufficient blood dregs are allowed the special honor of imbibing this blood. The sensually sweet gelatinous blood restores HP and temporarily speeds stamina recovery.</text>
<text>Blood taken from Adeline, patient of the research hall. Restores HP, then continues to rejuvenate HP for some time. Adeline was originally one of the Blood Saints who received treatment by the Church to cultivate worthy blood. Adeline's was one of the few cases that turned out favorably.</text>
<text>Special bullets used with hunter firearms. Ordinary bullets have no effect on beasts, and so Quicksilver Bullets, fused with the wielder's own blood, must be employed. The strength of Quicksilver Bullets depends greatly upon the wielder's bloodtinge.</text>
<text>Special equivalents to Quicksilver Bullets. When a hunter runs out of Quicksilver Bullets, it is possible to create bullets purely from blood. Beware of overuse, as their creation greatly drains HP.</text>
<text>Special blood used in ministration. Restores HP. Once a patient has had their blood ministered, a unique but common treatment in Yharnam, successive infusions recall the first, and are all the more invigorating for it. No surprise that most Yharnamites are heavy users of blood.</text>
<text>Small medicinal tablets that counteract poison. Used to treat ashen blood, the baffling sickness that ravaged Old Yharnam long ago. These tablets only provide short-term relief. The ashen blood ailment eventually triggered the spread of the beastly scourge.</text>
<text>Liquid medicine concocted at Byrgenwerth. Calms the nerves. Those who delve into the arcane fall all-too-easily to madness, and thick human blood serves to calm the frayed nerves of these inquisitive minds. Naturally, this often leads to a reliance on blood ministration.</text>
<text>Large medicinal pellets, supposedly formed of coagulated beast blood. Banned by the Healing Church due to their unclear origin. Grants a spurt of beasthood. Ripping apart the flesh of one's enemies and being rained upon by their splattering blood invigorates one's sense of beasthood, feeding strength and euphoric feeling alike.</text>
<text>Dubious liquid medicine used in strange experiments conducted by high ministers of the Healing Church. A type of anesthetic that numbs the brain. Hunters, able to retain consciousness by force of will, make use of a secondary effect of the medicine, which dilutes their presence while standing still.</text>
<text>Explodes in raging flames when thrown against an object. One of the oldest hunter tools available in the workshop. Since the tragedy that struck Old Yharnam, fire has become a staple in beast hunts, and is thought to cleanse impurity. Certain types of beasts have an abnormal fear of flame.</text>
<text>A special hunter tool crafted by the old Oto Workshop. These molotovs wedge into the ground when thrown, and explode on a timed delay. A shame that such a complex gadget must be sacrificed with each use of this inefficient hunter tool. Nevertheless, delayed molotovs are cherished by the minority of hunters who prefer the tricksier kill. This creation is one of the earliest-known roots of the Powder Kegs.</text>
<text>A knife slathered in poison. This curved knife is as thin and sharp as a surgeon's blade. Often used for self-defense by special doctors in the Healing Church.  They say that hunters traditionally avoid the use of poison, likely because the poison is too slow to act in the heat of the hunt.</text>
<text>When this urn hits its mark, the target is drenched in oil, and made extremely flammable. Fire is commonplace on the hunt, and oil urns accentuate its effect. Sometimes, when hunters burn beasts, they appear intoxicated by the euphoria of purification.</text>
<text>Small pebbles found throughout Yharnam. Can be thrown at foes.  Quite thrilling.</text>
<text>Throwing knife with a finely serrated blade. One of the old hunter Henryk's favorite weapons. Does not cause a great deal of damage to beasts, but with deft use, can distract attackers and keep them at bay.</text>
<text>Exploding Molotov cocktail that is thrown behind. Allows for more maneuvering compared to an ordinary Molotov cocktail, and can catch foes off guard. Since the tragedy that struck Old Yharnam, fire has become a staple in beast hunts, and is thought to cleanse impurity. Certain types of beasts have an abnormal fear of flame.</text>
<text>A special hunter tool crafted by the old Oto Workshop. These molotovs wedge into the ground when thrown behind one's back, and explode on a timed delay. A shame that such a complex gadget must be sacrificed with each use of this inefficient hunter tool. Nevertheless, delayed molotovs are cherished by the minority of hunters who prefer the tricksier kill. This creation is one of the earliest-known roots of the Powder Kegs.</text>
<text>Mature blood cocktail that releases a pungent odor when thrown that attracts blood-thirsty beasts. A precious tool in sadly short supply. In Yharnam, they produce more blood than alcohol, as the former is the more intoxicating.</text>
<text>Throw to create a mist cloud that numbs a hunter's life essence and prevents restoration of HP. Said to be used by the blood hunters of Cainhurst, its recipe is a secret closely guarded by the line of nobles inhabiting the castle.</text>
<text>Coarse paper that applies fire to weapons when rubbed. A hunter tool found in the Healing Church workshop. Since the tragedy that struck Old Yharnam, fire has become a staple in beast hunts, and is thought to cleanse impurity. Certain types of beasts have an abnormal fear of flame.</text>
<text>Empty invertebrate shell that is said to be a familiar of a Great One. The Healing Church has discovered a great variety of invertebrates, or phantasms, as they are called. Shells with slime still harbor arcane power, and can be rubbed on weapons to imbue them with their strength.</text>
<text>Coarse paper that applies bolt to weapons when rubbed. Invented by Archibald, the infamous eccentric of the Healing Church workshop. Artificially recreates the blue sparks that are said to surround darkbeasts. Unlike the other strange weapons created by Archibald, this one was favored by many hunters, in particular those who had even once laid eyes on a darkbeast.</text>
<text>Additional medium that strengthens Quicksilver Bullets. According to the workshop, this is a special bone marrow ash collected from Hemwick Charnel Lane. Invaluable to hunters with weak bloodtinge who require the use of stronger firearms.</text>
<text>Dangling, upside-down rune etched in the mind of a hunter. The image upon this parchment allows one to envision the rune with clarity. Allows a hunter to awaken again without losing Blood Echoes, a trick that seems nearly too good to be true.</text>
<text>Various coins that are particularly luminous. There are very few uses for spare change during the hunt, but these will serve as guides through the darkness. Or, one could save them until morning, if it ever comes.</text>
<text>Monocular used to view things up close. Not a hunter's tool, but a simple antique, to be used as one sees fit.</text>
<text>Small portable lantern. This hunting accessory provides light while leaving both hands free to hold weapons. The torch, however, provides a stronger source of light.</text>
<text>Skull of a madman touched by the wisdom of the Great Ones. Use to gain Insight. Making contact with eldritch wisdom is a blessing, for even if it drives one mad, it allows one to serve a grander purpose, for posterity.</text>
<text>Fragments of the lost wisdom of the Great Ones, beings that might be described as gods. Use to gain Insight. At Byrgenwerth, Master Willem had an epiphany: "We are thinking on the basest of planes. What we need, are more eyes."</text>
<text>Droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes. Use to gain Blood Echoes. Hunters sustained by the dream gain strength from Blood Echoes. They imbibe the blood with thoughts of reverence, indeed gratitude, for their victims.</text>
<text>A thick droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes. Use to gain a larger amount of Blood Echoes. A strong will produces thick blood. Doubtless, the product of obsession, a potent source of human strength.</text>
<text>A rich droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes. Use to gain frenzied Blood Echoes. This manifestation of madness comes from a mind teetering on the very brink, but has a sane mind ever produced anything of true significance?</text>
<text>Coldblood of inhuman kin of the cosmos, brethren of the Great Ones. Use to gain unspeakable Blood Echoes. Dare not to delve into the world beyond humanity, the eldritch Truth touched upon long ago at Byrgenwerth.</text>
<text>Relic containing the Blood Echoes of a Great One. Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes. Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies understanding.</text>
<text>Relic containing the Blood Echoes of an old Great One. Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes. Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies understanding.</text>
<text>Relic containing the Blood Echoes of a revered Great One. Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes. Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies understanding.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Clockwise Metamorphosis" rune raises HP.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Anti-Clockwise Metamorphosis" rune raises stamina.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Communion" rune raises blood vial maximum.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Oedon Liaison" rune increases Quicksilver Bullet maximum.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Lake" rune increases defense.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Deep Sea" rune increases resistance.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Destroyer" rune strengthens visceral attacks.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Reveler" rune makes visceral attacks restore HP.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Liaison" rune makes visceral attacks restore Quicksilver Bullets.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Heir" rune makes visceral attacks grant more Blood Echoes.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Beast" rune boosts effect of temporary transformation.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Moon" rune grants additional Blood Echoes.</text>
<text>A page from the lost book of runesmith Caryll. Caryll devoted his life to transcribing the sounds spoken by the Great Ones. Read a Caryll Rune to assume its form. The "Eye" rune allows one to make additional discoveries.</text>
<text>A centipede-like creature discovered on successful hunts by League hunters. Vermin, found hidden within filth, are only seen by League confederates, and are the root of man's impurity. The League has assumed the task of finding and crushing all vermin. Perhaps there is some mercy in the madness. Those who wish to see vermin can, and those who choose to are provided with boundless purpose.</text>
<text>Remnant of the eldritch Truth encountered at Byrgenwerth. Use phantasms, the invertebrates known to be augurs of the Great Ones, to partially summon abandoned Ebrietas. The initial encounter marked the start of an inquiry into the cosmos from within the old labyrinth, and led to the establishment of the Choir.</text>
<text>One of the secret rites of the Choir. Long ago, the Healing Church used phantasms to reach a lofty plane of darkness, but failed to make contact with the outer reaches of the cosmos.  The rite failed to achieve its intended purpose, but instead created a small exploding star, now a powerful part of the Choir's arsenal. At times, failure is the mother of invention.</text>
<text>One of the forbidden hunter tools made by Irreverent Izzy. Borrow the strength of the terrible undead darkbeasts, if only for a moment, to blast surrounding foes back with the force of a roaring beast.  The indescribable sound is broadcast with the caster's own vocal cords, which begs the question, what terrible things lurk deep within the frames of men?</text>
<text>A heavy, syrupy liquid medicine. Temporarily shifts weight to make deflection of attacks easier, but must be used with care, as it also slows movement with no change to defense. Its recipe for this mysterious concoction is unknown, but some postulate that it materializes only within the most desperate nightmares.</text>
<text>Special hunter tool of the Choir, high-ranking members of the church. Fashioned after a bell that projects an arcane sound across planes of existence. The sound of this smaller, silver version of the bell does not cross planes, but grants vigor and healing to all cooperators.</text>
<text>The bone of an old hunter whose name is lost. It is said that he was an apprentice to old Gehrman, and a practitioner of the art of Quickening, a technique particular to the first hunters. It is most appropriate that hunters, carriers of the torch who are sustained by the dream, would tease an old art from his remains.</text>
<text>Tonitrus is a unique weapon crafted by Archibald, the infamous eccentric of the Healing Church workshop. This is a similar morning star mace that utilizes Quicksilver Bullets. When struck into the ground, it recreates the blue sparks that are said to surround the darkbeasts.  Like Archibald's masterpiece, this too is a superb conductor of the powerful blue sparks.</text>
<text>One of the secret treasures hidden in Cainhurst. The gloves of an executioner from a faraway land. Passed from executioner father to executioner son, these gloves can be used to summon wrathful spirits of the past by smearing them with blood. It is said that the nobles found immeasurable delight in the dances of these vengeful specters.</text>
<text>A blade of bone coated with gruesome spinal fluid. Used by old labyrinth Watchers, in particular, those presiding over rituals. When a victim is cut by this blade, the green spinal fluid temporarily numbs the senses, disturbing the target's gross motor skills. The blade, never intended for battle, must cut deep to be effective, and breaks.</text>
<text>A strange gift from the messengers, inhabitants of the dream who revere the brave hunters. Use to envelop oneself in a black nightmarish mist, then transform into a messenger. The illusion is a parlor trick, and any large movement will break the spell. To preserve the guise, proceed very slowly.</text>
<text>Soft eye blessed by a phantasm. They were discovered through Byrgenwerth's contact with the arcane, but in the end revealed nothing. Deep within the eye lies a vast stretch of dark sky that rumbles with an endless meteor storm. The slightest rub of the tiny orb, and the rock will tumble and soar.</text>
<text>Skull of a local from the violated fishing village. The inside of the skull was forcibly searched for eyes, as evidenced by innumerable scratches and indentations. No wonder the skull became stewed in curses. They who offer baneful chants. Weep with them, as one in trance.</text>
<text>Whistle of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods. The twins grew up alongside a poisonous snake, and developed a silent, inhuman kinship. The poisonous snake grew uncontrollably, raised on a healthy diet of beast entrails. Even after their deaths, it is said to respond to the call of the twins' whistle from within the Nightmare.</text>
<text>A solid shard that forms in coldblood. After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that which does not crystalize is called a blood stone. At the workshop, these bloodstones are embedded in weapons to fortify them.</text>
<text>A solid shard that forms in coldblood. After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that which does not crystalize is called a blood stone. At the workshop, these bloodstones are embedded in weapons to fortify them.</text>
<text>A solid chunk that forms in coldblood. After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that which does not crystalize is called a blood stone. A chunk will never appear in the blood of an ordinary human. Seek deadlier foes if bloodstone chunks are needed.</text>
<text>A large solid chunk that forms in coldblood. After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that which does not crystalize is called a blood stone. This is no mere chunk, it is nearly a boulder. Few blood stones of such size have ever been discovered, even considering the combined experience of all the hunters.</text>
<text>Key to the gate that blocks the Tomb of Oedon. Beyond the tomb, Oedon Chapel can be found in the center of the Cathedral Ward. Only today the church is abandoned, and some say that the residents of Oedon have all gone mad.</text>
<text>Pendant of Vicar Amelia. Use to change into a blood gem, which fortifies weapons. This pendant, passed down among the vicars who head the Healing Church, is a reminder of the cautionary adage, words that will open the gates of Byrgenwerth.</text>
<text>An old blood-stained summons, inviting an honored guest to the forsaken Castle Cainhurst. Rather bafflingly, it is addressed to you. Do not hesitate; the stagecoach leaves from Hemwick crossing.</text>
<text>Key to the Orphanage, birthplace of the Choir. The Orphanage, shadowed by the Grand Cathedral, was a place of scholarship and experimentation, where young orphans became potent unseen thinkers for the Healing Church.  The Choir, that would later split the Healing Church, was a creation of the Orphanage.</text>
<text>Of the three great bridges that link the two cathedral cradles, this key opens the iron door that leads to the midlevel bridge. There are no thieves in the nightmare. Then, why lock a door? Be warned, there must be a very, very good reason.</text>
<text>The key to the Upper Cathedral Ward seal. The upper echelons of the Healing Church are formed by the School of Mensis, based in the Unseen Village, and the Choir occupying the Upper Cathedral Ward. This key brings one a step closer to the Choir.</text>
<text>A cloth emblem that belonged to the captain of the Church hunters long ago. Opens the main gate that leads to the round plaza of the Great Cathedral. The main gate is shut tight on nights of the hunt, and could only be opened from the other side with this emblem. In other words, the captain's return, and this emblem, determined the end of the hunt.</text>
<text>Key to the Lecture Theatre in the Lecture Building. Today, the two-story Lecture Building is adrift in the nightmare, but once it was a place of reflection, where scholars learned of history and archaeology. Perhaps it still is, as the students in the lecture theatre appear to await the return of their professor.</text>
<text>Key to the lunarium facing the lake on the second floor of Byrgenwerth College. In his final years, Master Willem was fond of the lookout, and the rocking chair that he kept there for meditation. In the end, it is said, he left his secret with the lake.</text>
<text>Skull of Laurence, first vicar of the Healing Church. In reality he became the first cleric beast, and his human skull only exists within the Nightmare. The skull is a symbol of Laurence's past, and what he failed to protect. He is destined to seek his skull, but even if he found it, it could never restore his memories.</text>
<text>Key to the inner chamber of the cell below the Grand Cathedral. The innermost chamber of the underground cell holds a lone madman. He wears a beast hide, and rings a bell that emits no sound. Unending death awaits those who can hear the soundless bell.</text>
<text>An eye pendant which unlocks the surgery altar. There are two cathedrals in the Hunter's Dream. One lies past the River of Blood, and another contains the private research hall of the Healing Church. Only chosen members of the Healing Church, or their lamentable patients, can enter the research hall, using this eye. Grant eyes to the surgery altar skull.</text>
<text>Key to the cell below the Grand Cathedral. Hunters are held within the underground cell, so that things better left unseen, and knowledge better left unknown, will decay quietly in the fallow darkness.</text>
<text>Key to the balcony on the first floor of the Research Hall. Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower gave this to the patient, Adeline. Maria had hoped Adeline would find comfort in the faint breeze that carried the scent of flowers from the outside, but Adeline couldn't fathom her intentions.</text>
<text>Key to the Astral Clocktower at the top of the Grand Cathedral. The caretaker of the tower's numerous patients, known to them only as Lady Maria, made her home behind the giant star-interpreting clock.</text>
<text>A celestial dial that functions with the giant Astral Clock in the Grand Cathedral. When the dial is held up toward the Astral Clock, the clock will come to life, and reveal a secret to its curious interloper.</text>
<text>A misplaced workshop tool from the Hunter's Dream. The hunter who retrieves this can extract Arcane Haze from ritual materials. But alas, spent materials are lost.</text>
<text>A misplaced workshop tool from the Hunter's Dream. The hunter who retrieves this can fortify weapons by kneading blood gems into them. Blood gems add properties to weapons when used to fortify them, as blood defines an organism.</text>
<text>Runesmith Caryll, student of Byrgenwerth, transcribed the inhuman utterings of the Great Ones into what are now called Caryll Runes. The hunter who retrieves this workshop tool can etch Caryll Runes into the mind to attain their wondrous strength. Provost Willem would have been proud of Caryll's runes, as they do not rely upon blood in any measure.</text>
<text>One of the root chalices that breaks various seals in the Old Labyrinth. The glass chalice, when full, is used in a short ritual to quickly create and join a Chalice Dungeon (not for use in a ritual using standard materials). Short rituals are conducted at the makeshift altar.</text>
<text>Badge crafted long ago at the Workshop. Attests to one's prowess as a hunter of beasts. The Workshop is gone, and no group recognizes this meaningless badge, except the messengers in the bath, who understand its profundity. Certain things can only be entrusted with a hunter in possession of this badge, or so they believe.</text>
<text>Badge of a Hunter of Hunters, who hunts those who have become addled with blood. The badge of the Hunter of Hunters is quietly passed down from generation to generation, usually to an outsider from the hinterlands. To be entrusted with this cursed badge, one must be strong, resilient to the seduction of blood, and gracious when taking a comrade's life.</text>
<text>Badge crafted by the Powder Kegs, the heretics of the Workshop. The Powder Kegs adoration of complex design and big booms culminated in weapon designs that contrast with those traditionally of the Workshop. The late Powder Kegs, bless their souls, had a motto: "If a weapon ain't got kick, it just ain't worth it."</text>
<text>This hunter's badge, crafted in Gehrman's time, has no practical purpose, except perhaps to assist in romanticizing about the past. The badge was a special privilege for the hunters of the past, and should not be dishonored. It should be left in peace, unless one is truly prepared to assume the will of those gone before.</text>
<text>One of the badges crafted by the Healing Church. The silver sword is a symbol of a Church hunter. Ludwig was the first of many Healing Church hunters to come, many of whom were clerics. As it was, clerics transformed into the most hideous beasts.</text>
<text>One of the badges crafted by the Healing Church. The radiant sword indicates the heirs to the will of Ludwig. These hunters, also known as Holy Blades, are what remains of an ancient line of heroes that date back to a very early age of honor and chivalry.</text>
<text>Martyr Logarius led a band of Executioners, and this badge was crafted at their dedicated workshop. The wheel symbolizes righteous destiny. Their workshop was a secretive enclave of mystical beliefs and heady fanaticism which served as the backbone of the Executioners' unique brand of justice.</text>
<text>Badge of the royal guards of Cainhurst, loyal guardians of the Vileblood Queen Annalise. The Vilebloods are hunters of blood, and hunt prey as they search for blood dregs. The hunter who joins them is faced with a decision: to merely borrow their strength, or to become one of them, heart and soul.</text>
<text>Badge crafted in secret by Archibald, the infamous eccentric of the Healing Church, for his friends. Archibald was fascinated by the blue sparks that emanate from the hides of the darkbeasts, and dedicated his life to its artificial reproduction, in a style of inquiry that, incidentally, closely followed the methodology of Byrgenwerth.</text>
<text>Badge of a member of the Choir, elites of the Healing Church. The eye signifies the very cosmos. The Choir stumbled upon an epiphany, very suddenly and quite by accident. Here we stand, feet planted in the earth, but might the cosmos be very near us, only just above our heads?</text>
<text>Badge crafted by the Oto Workshop, precursor to the workshop of the heretical Powder Kegs. The Powder Kegs were driven by singular ideas, and crafted strange weapons of great intricacy. It is clear that the philosophy of the Powder Kegs was already established at this time.</text>
<text>A small, very ordinary hair ornament. Although it has been lost for quite some time, one can still see signs of the care with which this tasteful ornament was once kept. Its color would stand out most brilliantly against a head of grayish hair.</text>
<text>Silver-shining tear stone. Use to change into a droplet blood gem that fortifies any weapon. A doll sheds neither blood nor tears, and thus its nature remains unknown. Whoever thinks this is precious must be troubled by severe naiveté.</text>
<text>The inhuman beings known as the Great Ones imbued this ring of betrothal with some special meaning. In the age of the Great Ones, wedlock was a blood contract, only permitted to those slated to bear a special child.</text>
<text>What remains of Annalise, blood queen of Cainhurst. This pinkish lump of flesh remains warm, as if cursed. All hail the undying queen of blood!</text>
<text>A woman's bright-red brooch, engraved with the name Viola. Perhaps the jewel is a gift from a hunter. Use to change into a droplet blood gem that fortifies any weapon. With the proper workshop tool, various weapons can be fortified.</text>
<text>An old, sealed summons. Like the first of its kind, it is an invitation to Cainhurst, but for whom is not known, as it lacks an addressee.</text>
<text>A latticed, deformed rock, or perhaps a meteorite. Appears useless, but possesses some odd gravitational force that prevents its riddance. A dubious soul once said: "Step lightly round to the right of the great cathedral, and seek an ancient, shrouded church... The gift of the godhead will grant you strength..."</text>
<text>The eye of a blood-drunk hunter. Its pupil is collapsed and turned to mush, indicating the onset of the scourge of beasts. A hunter who goes drunk with blood is said to be taken by the Nightmare, destined to wander forever, engaged in an endless hunt. It is a fate that no hunter can escape.</text>
<text>One of the resonating bells that cross the gaps of worlds. This bell is cracked and stained with the blood of beasts. A human must expend Insight to ring this uncanny bell. The old hunters, who have long passed from the dream but cannot forget the feeling of the hunt, rely upon messengers to relay their thoughts. Ring the bell at their side, and they are certain to give a listen. For the night of the hunt is long, and unchanging.</text>
<text>A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord. Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate. The Third Umbilical Cord precipitated the encounter with the pale moon, which beckoned the hunters and conceived the Hunter's Dream. Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside, although no one remembers what that truly entails.</text>
<text>A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord. Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate, and Oedon, the formless Great One, is no different. To think, it was corrupted blood that began this eldritch liaison. Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside, although no one remembers what that truly entails.</text>
<text>A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord. Provost Willem sought the Cord in order to elevate his being and thoughts to those of a Great One, by lining his brain with eyes. The only choice, he knew, if man were to ever match Their greatness.</text>
<text>A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord. Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate. This Cord granted Mensis audience with Mergo, but resulted in the stillbirth of their brains. Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside, although no one remembers what that truly entails.</text>
<text>A sacred heirloom left by Yharnam, Pthumerian Queen. The Queen lies dead, but her horrific consciousness is only asleep, and stirs in unsettling motions.</text>
<text>Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces. Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that was all that they were. Once, a young girl had an older brother who was determined to become a doctor, and so she willfully became his patient. In the end, this led to their encounter with the Eldritch Truth, for which they considered themselves blessed.</text>
<text>Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces. Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that was all that they were. In the early days of the Healing Church, the Great Ones were linked to the ocean, and so the cerebral patients would imbibe water, and listen for the howl of the sea. Brain fluid writhed inside the head, the initial makings of internal eyes.</text>
<text>Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces. Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that was all that they were. We fail to realize our own latent potential, until the moment it is lost, and we sense its absence. Ironically, this is the very nature of insight, like the moment one licks one's own blood, only to be startled by its sweetness.</text>
<text>Hat that messengers are oddly fond of. Commonly called a Yharnam hat. The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?</text>
<text>A worn, rumpled top hat that messengers are oddly fond of. The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?</text>
<text>Accessory adored by naïve messengers imitating the bandages of scourge victims, unaware of their meaning. The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?</text>
<text>White ribbon that messengers are oddly fond of. A ribbon made of fine lace that shines remarkably, more suited to pretty young girls than silly old messengers.</text>
<text>Red ribbon that messengers are oddly fond of. The thick, pungent red was drawn from the organs of some unfortunate victim. A strange choice indeed, but perhaps for the messengers wearing this accessory constitutes a form of mourning.</text>
<text>Hat that messengers are oddly fond of. A nice top hat rounds out any Yharnam gentleman. The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?</text>
<text>Hat that messengers are oddly fond of. Symbol of the preventative hunters of the Healing Church. The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?</text>
<text>Accessory adored by naïve messengers imitating the bandages of scourge victims, unaware of their meaning. The spatters of blood give it a particularly nice touch. The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?</text>
<text>Accessory adored by naïve messengers. The messengers wear the urns, filled with incense that wards off beasts, on their heads upside-down, suggesting a predilection to the dark. The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians, superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.</text>
<text>Ritual chalice found in the Church of the Good Chalice. Use in a ritual at the tomb altar in the Hunter's Dream to break the seal of the old underground labyrinth. Let the chalice reveal the tomb of the gods; let blood be the hunter's nourishment. ...And let ye partake in communion...</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians, superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. But only a Root Chalice changes the shape of the old labyrinth when used in a ritual. The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians, superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. The hintertombs are unceremonious homes to graves and death, cesspools of noxious snakes and insects.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. Hintertombs are the peripheral catacombs of the old underground labyrinth. To this day, the Watchers continue to expand the hintertombs, unceremonious catacombs filled with graves and death.</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians, superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.</text>
<text>Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be a mad Pthumerian. The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians, superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the wisdom of the eldritch Truth. Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only. The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. But only a Root Chalice changes the shape of the old labyrinth when used in a ritual. The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians, superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. The hintertombs are unceremonious homes to graves and death, cesspools of noxious snakes and insects.</text>
<text>Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be a mad Pthumerian. The hintertombs are unceremonious homes to graves and death, cesspools of noxious snakes and insects. Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only. The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. Hintertombs are the peripheral catacombs of the old underground labyrinth. To this day, the Watchers continue to expand the hintertombs, unceremonious catacombs filled with graves and death.</text>
<text>Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. This cursed chalice makes a special ritual possible, but must not be used lightly, as the resulting transformation can be utterly drastic. The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians, superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. Only, this defiled chalice is cursed. Curses are caused by inciting the anger of the Great Ones, and used to hex others. Special materials are required to complete the ritual. To try one's hand at curses, first seek the Bastard of Loran.</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. There are trace remains of medical procedures in parts of ailing Loran. Whether these were attempts to control the scourge of the beast, or the cause of the outbreak, is unknown.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. Loran is a tragic land that was devoured by the sands. The tragedy that struck this ailing land of Loran is said to have its roots in the scourge of the beast. Some have made the dreaded extrapolation that Yharnam may be next.</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. The Pthumerian monarch was traditionally a woman who assumed a name with classical roots.</text>
<text>Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be a mad Pthumerian. The Pthumerian monarch was traditionally a woman who assumed a name with classical roots. Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only. The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. Great chalices unlock deeper reaches of the labyrinth. Pthumeru Ihyll was the title of both the Pthumerian monarch and its capital. This reveals that while early Pthumerians were mere humble guardians of the slumbering Great Ones, their descendants felt entitled to name themselves a leader.</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. There are trace remains of medical procedures in parts of ailing Loran. Whether these were attempts to control the scourge of the beast, or the cause of the outbreak, is unknown.</text>
<text>Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be a mad Pthumerian. There are trace remains of medical procedures in parts of ailing Loran. Whether these were attempts to control the scourge of the beast, or the cause of the outbreak, is unknown. Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only. The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. But only a Root Chalice changes the shape of the Chalice Dungeon when used in a ritual. There are trace remains of medical procedures in parts of ailing Loran. Whether these were attempts to control the scourge of the beast, or the cause of the outbreak, is unknown.</text>
<text>Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time. According to the Choir, the land of Isz lies in contact with the cosmos, which allowed the Great Ones to function on transcendental planes of thought.</text>
<text>Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals. When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be a mad Pthumerian. According to the Choir, the land of Isz lies in contact with the cosmos, which allowed the Great Ones to function on transcendental planes of thought. Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only. The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.</text>
<text>A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal. Great chalices unlock deeper reaches of the labyrinth. The Great Isz Chalice became the cornerstone of the Choir, the elite delegation of the Healing Church. It was also the first Great Chalice brought back to the surface since the time of Byrgenwerth, and allowed the Choir to have audience with Ebrietas.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. One of the basic ingredients used to satiate a Holy Chalice is this incoagulable blood. When all is melted in blood, all is reborn.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. The remains of a skull used in a ceremony. A vestige of the bizarre rites carried out by the old labyrinth Watchers.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. A perfect specimen, surrounded by a faint flame. A vestige of the bizarre rites carried out by the old labyrinth Watchers.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood inside the old labyrinth.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a place long ago abandoned.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a place long abandoned, said to mature slowly in close proximity to death, and eventually bloom.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a place long abandoned, that has bloomed into a bright red stygian flower.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Pale bulb that commonly grows on coldblood inside the old labyrinth, said to mature slowly in the abyss, and eventually bloom.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood inside the old labyrinth that has bloomed into a bright red stygian flower.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Mold that grows from rotten flesh and blood inside the old labyrinth. Matures to bear giant spores.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Mold that grows from rotten flesh and blood inside the old labyrinth. Matures to bear giant spores.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Mold that grows from rotten flesh and blood inside the old labyrinth. Its giant spores eventually break off and float into the air, the best moment to use the mold as a material.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. The tiny smatterings of haze that are found in certain ritual materials. Sometimes required for special rites. The additional rite Sinister Bell makes the bell-ringing woman appear, and when she rings a sinister bell, hunters from other worlds will be beckoned as adversaries.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Of the all the strange lifeforms that reside in the nooks and crannies of the old labyrinth, the slugs are clear signs of the left-behind Great Ones.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. One of the basic ingredients used to satiate a Holy Chalice is this incoagulable blood. When all is melted in blood, all is reborn.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. One of the basic ingredients used to satiate a Holy Chalice is this incoagulable blood. When all is melted in blood, all is reborn.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Stillborn infants born of a creature of unknown origin, of the type found in some corners of the old labyrinth.</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Strange creatures lurk in the nooks and crannies of the old labyrinth.</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Strange creatures lurk in the nooks and crannies of the old labyrinth.</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. A body part of a saint, sacrificed by the Healing Church in their search for Truth. The additional rite Fetid Offering invigorates the Watchers, making them more treacherous than normal, but also making them worthy prey for a special hunt.</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. A body part of a saint, sacrificed by the Healing Church in their search for Truth. The Church's experiments with blood have successfully produced specimens perfect for sacrifice.</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Special body parts collected by the Healing Church. What was this gruesome bait used to lure? The additional rite Rotted Offering beckons ungodly forces, normally terrifying things, but also worthy prey for a special hunt.</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. Remains of Loran infant infected by the scourge. A harbinger of curses and symbol of defilement. The additional rite Curse defiles dungeons in which hunters' HP is greatly eroded, but what better place to seek cursed blood gems but in the midst of defilement?</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. A stillborn infant born of a creature of unknown origin, of the type found in some corners of the old labyrinth. The apprentices of Byrgenwerth were fascinated by newborns, perhaps due to the stunning quality of these remains.</text>
<text>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. An exquisite eyeball removed quickly after death, or perhaps even before. Used to unlock the seal of the old labyrinth hintertombs.</text>
<text>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual. The immense brain that Mensis retrieved from the nightmare was indeed lined with eyes on the inside, but they were of an evil sort, and the brain itself was terribly rotten. But even still, it was a legitimate Great One, and left a relic. A living relic, at that, which is a precious thing indeed.</text>

</entries>